Suffering is a fact of life. Either you learn to
deal with that... or you go under.
Silent Hill: Revelation 3D is a thriller, horror,
mystery film directed by MJ Bassett.
Heather Mason and her father have been on the run, always one step ahead
of dangerous forces that she doesn't fully understand.
Now on the eve of her 18th birthday, plagued by horrific nightmares and the
disappearance of her father, Heather discovers she's not who she thinks she is.
The revelation leads her deeper into a demonic world
that threatens to trap her forever.
Heather Mason / Sharon Da Silva / Alessa, played by Adelaide Clemens.
Harry Mason / Christopher Da Silva, played by Sean Bean.
Rose Da Silva, played by Radha Mitchell.
Claudia Wolf, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Leonard Wolf, played by Malcolm McDowell.
Vincent Carter, played by Kit Harington.
Silent Hill: Revelation (also known as Silent Hill: Revelation 3D) is a 2012 supernatural horror film based on the video
game series Silent Hill published by Konami, and is the second installment in the Silent Hill film series.
A sequel to Silent Hill (2006), the film was written and directed by M.
It stars Adelaide Clemens, Kit Harington, Martin Donovan, Malcolm McDowell, and Carrie-Anne Moss, with
Deborah Kara Unger, Sean Bean, and Radha Mitchell returning from the previous film.
The plot follows Heather Mason (Clemens), who, discovering on the eve of her eighteenth
birthday that her presumed identity is false, is drawn to the town of Silent Hill.
Talks for a Silent Hill sequel began in December 2006, with
Christophe Gans returning to direct and Roger Avary writing.
However, after Gans dropped out and Avary was imprisoned for vehicular
manslaughter, the project entered development hell.
Later, in early 2010, Bassett was hired to direct
and write, replacing Gans and Avary.
On an estimated $20 million budget, filming took place from March to May 2011 in Canada, with
the 3D RED Epic camera used for the process; audio mixing took place in France.
Silent Hill: Revelation was released theatrically in North America on October 26, 2012, by Alliance Films
and Open Road Films respectively; in France on November 28, by Metropolitan Filmexport.
The film grossed over $55.9 million worldwide and
received largely negative reviews from critics.
A third film, Return to Silent Hill, was released on January 23, 2026.
The film explores themes of sequel, female protagonist,
another dimension, based on video game, occult.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.